# Samuel Muiruri

Python / Django developer (Full Stack) Email: muiruri.samuel@gmail.com

**Age:** 27 **Phone No:** +254 738 940 064

**LinkedIn:** <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-muiruri-a5235532/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-muiruri-a5235532/</a> **Stackoverflow:** <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow:</a> <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow:</a> <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow:</a> <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow:</a> <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri">https://stackoverflow.com/users/6355473/samuel-muiruri</a>

Github: <a href="https://github.com/Six-wars">https://github.com/Six-wars</a>

I've got +5 years experience in Django and almost expertise level in Python.

I have experience working alone on projects and in a team of developers.

Comfortable with front-end development and have been left in charge of running, migrating and maintaining server of popular site(s).

# **Tools worth mentioning**

➤ **Nginx:** familiar with it, use it always.

- **Gunicorn:** also familiar and use it mainly.
- > AWS: migrated a django site to AWS
- **Django 1.8:** *latest version I've used so far.*
- **▶ Jquery & Bootsrap:** *my preferred front-end tools.*
- **django-allauth:** used to setup Oauth accounts for facebook, twitter, and more.
- **django-rest-framework:** worth mentioning, used on a demo site only.
- **matplotlib:** *I* used it to create a few simple graphs, from the docs know it's full capabilities.
- **reportlab:** *I* used it to create Movie Ticket pdf's for KenyaBuzz
- ➤ **Angularjs:** have used it only to get a feel of how it works
- **virtualenv:** implemented it on <u>pluscolor.co.ke</u> where Django site runs on top of a virtualenv
- **Selenium:** *useful for automation browser processes and testing user activity*
- ➤ Extjs: for a job pre-interview was required to prove proficiency with this tool. Useful because it can allow one to render aspects of website like tables with filters from javascript code alone. This can reduce development time by including a list of comprehensive and complete tools in a bootstrap; neat looking format. Final presentation (passed pre-interview): <a href="https://jsfiddle.net/w5tuf1fn/1/">https://jsfiddle.net/w5tuf1fn/1/</a> & <a href="https://jsfiddle.net/2nskoed2/1/">https://jsfiddle.net/w5tuf1fn/1/</a> & <a href="https://jsfiddle.net/2nskoed2/1/">https://jsfiddle.net/2nskoed2/1/</a>. Intent was to list users from csv using extjs and display in form and highlight (anyway you want) users who have exceeded the planned End Date.

### **Education**

**K.C.S.E** (Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education) **Grade:** C+ : 2006 - 2009

*Kenyatta University:* **Diploma in Information Technology** : 2011 – 2012 (discontinued)

In the last year (2012) I was working full time at Lamu Software as a Django Developer, since my intent was to finish the course and pursue a course in Computer Science I re-evaluated and realized with skills from the field I could bridge into the course later on.

**Udacity:** <u>udacity.com</u>

Since it launched I've taken courses offered there like "Introduction to Artificial Intelligence".

*In my free time taking a course in Machine Learning.* 

# **Experience**

Before start of work history I worked for "Lamu Software" which was a startup specializing in developing sites using Django. I started here as a junior developer, the company later on closed.

After leaving Lamu Software (in between then and now) I have worked on a number of small projects, recent notable project specs; with "Vidi Reports" which returns facial recognition data such as; age, sex, mood, watching/not watching ... in json & send the data to django so on a screen (with a camera) show user based ads. For example have one ad for men and another for women and based on the majority gender play the ad.

# Kenya Buzz – kenyabuzz.com

2015 - 2017

I've worked here as a django developer in charge of maintaining the day to day running of the site. During this time I've honed my skills as a front-end dev and also improved in backend dev too.

Kenya Buzz is a *lifestyle website* which has lifestyle articles, events happening in Kenya, movie listing and the option to buy movie tickets for some theatres in Kenya. At the time I joined the ticketing was handled by another provider then hosted on the site using iframe. I since then moved it in house, set up the ticketing; *so you can select a seat, pay and get a ticket sent to your email.* 

I also worked on editing the front end to a more modern look.

**Note:** Early this year 2017, Nation Media Group acquired Kenya Buzz in a merger, from this came the task to migrate the site to AWS and later switch to PHP. Since I left they have finished testing and launching the new site.

Alix Grubel – Managing Director alix@kenyabuzz.com +254 733 620 998

### KaziLynk – <u>kazilynk.com</u>

2017 – to date

KaziLynk is a job listing site that *matches jobs to job seekers* and also *lists services* that target the Kenyan Market.

Soft Launch on October 2017.

Damaris Agweyu - Site Owner damaris@kazilynk.com +254 703 413 421

**Samuel Muiruri** – Main Developer <a href="mailto:support@kazilynk.com">support@kazilynk.com</a>

### +Color - pluscolor.co.ke

2017 – to date

Started by me (and still), **+Color** started as a gallery for images just showcasing example images transformed from black & white to coloured using machine learning, this also applied to images with color.

Example: <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/colourizer">https://pluscolor.co.ke/colourizer</a>

The above led to the core concept behind the galleries:

- <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/gallery">https://pluscolor.co.ke/gallery</a>
- <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/gallery?photo">https://pluscolor.co.ke/gallery?photo</a> id=130
- https://pluscolor.co.ke/african-history

There's also the timeline which shows images shared by users (incuding the results from +Color Apps): <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/timeline">https://pluscolor.co.ke/timeline</a>

### +Color Apps

### Color Picker: <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-picker">https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-picker</a>

Allows you to pick a color (by hex code) from an image by clicking the spot on the image. This is copied to your clipboard.

#### Color Editor: <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-editor">https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-editor</a>

Allows you to edit an image using "color rules". *Example*: <a href="https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-editor-example">https://pluscolor.co.ke/color-editor-example</a>

#### **Not yet launched** still figuring out sockets

Pre-sockets recording: https://youtu.be/E8VxffpCQ3w

#### *Color Delete:* https://pluscolor.co.ke/delete-color

Allows you to delete section(s) of an image: (works but without sockets)

Example: <a href="https://voutu.be/-EiCraPtVIY">https://voutu.be/-EiCraPtVIY</a>